Hello, everyone today. I have another Matlab tutorial video for you guys and as usual. [I] am providing
Limited number of free coupons for the course you'll be able to find [a] link in the [description] or you can go to the course
page and enter in the coupon Code YouTube
free there also be a discounted link to the course in the description if all the free coupons run out and
Of course you can always get the complete Matlab course bundle on my website
And you will get this course and for others for only $19
So if you enjoy the video leave a thumbs up and if you want to see more content like this please subscribe
So let's get started welcome [to] the course Matlab tutorial [from] beginner to Pro
So let's see what we have in this course this course essentially contains [10] different parrots in the first class we will be looking at
Instructor and the course introduction in section 2 we will be looking at how [to] declare variables and create your own scripts using Matlab
In chapter 3. We will be looking at basic. Math functions. That is the addition subtraction multiplication
greatest common [Devisor] least common division set operations statistical operations and many others
in Captor 4 we will be looking at [different] operation on the matrices that includes finding unique elements inside the Matrix shifting of a
Shifting operation on the Matrix finding determinants inverse and many other functions that are usually performed on the matrices
In chapter number five we will be looking at advanced math functions using the symbolic data type such as the integration
Function and then solving equations, and so many other different [types] of math operations
In chapter six we will be looking at different input output options and the graphics of Matlab for plotting the Euler graphs
In chapter 7 we will be looking at how to import data from [excel] and other environments into the Matlab
in Chapter 8
We will be looking at the basic Matlab programming and the basic
Constructs that make up the Matlab programming such as the itself and then the four moves and so many others
In chapter [nine], we will be demonstrating how to deliver on customized functions and the different options
And in chapter number can we will be looking at how you can share you [will] [yield] [results] [to] your colleagues friends and other
other friends if you want to share your [Matlab] code and results
Hello students. [I] am dr.. Nam on other and I teach courses on the online platform that is view the
teachable and Disclosure platforms
With regards to Matlab I have courses they spend wide variety of different topics
from F designing to data analysis to Matlab programming to Data structures I
Was introduced to Matlab during my graduate studies where back in
2007 and I use Matlab for different purposes such as data
visualization
such as this one and this one and doing data processing and data analysis and
Stem today Matlab is my number one choice for doing the same task
The key benefit of using Matlab that makes it number one choice for the researchers is that it is very quick to put ideas
into working product
During my decade-long experience with the Matlab I came across its different
functionality
And I explored majority of its programming aspects
and I used it to board the [applications] of the test [and] email filtering recommender systems and
I called the critical notions such as Camp Uri eruptive and many others
So in these courses which I have developed I actually put all [of] my experience into it
And you will really enjoy these courses in learning math lab and implies it on to your careers so see you in the courses
Hello students welcome to the new segment of the course in this segment
We [will] be looking at the journal way out of the Matlab software
So the first thing you may not is the command window [and] spending the majority of our screen [here]
So this is the place where actually we?
interact with the Matlab software
That is we give this give the software some input and expect some output
after that after being processed on the Matlab software
So that's where we are going to include certain commands, so for instance. We may say 8 plus 8 or we may
Do some meaningful?
Calculations right so you may consider it in there as a part of big calculator
But it of course it is beyond. It's beyond the basic calculator like it can perform certain other
Complex tasks as well
So the first thing we [note] [it] is this command window
And it is the place where go we are going to interact with the Matlab software
so the other
Portions of this same screen we may not hear another window. Which is called the current window
It is a dedicated folder
For the programs that we will put the [programs] [and] scrape [the] people develop using the Matlab software
And by default it [has] to appear over here
So if you want to change the location of the default directory where the Matlab should find your newer programs that you want to execute?
So then you may change it from here manually right so you can click over [here] and then?
Select the appropriate directory where your files are?
Where your files or program are being stored?
You can also change it from here as well, right?
so if you want to go to that specific folder
But remember [that] you cannot go up in the directory from here
You need to actually select it from here, and then you have the option to select the lower level directories from here
like so that's
That's the current folder of windows, and then we have another
Another window which is called the workspace
So remember that when we get some [completion] over here something
Appears in the name of a s over here with the corresponding value, and so if we do some more calculations
For instance 8-10 so we note [that] all sudden a value change has been occurred over here
right
So this ans is basically a default variable which will hold the computation that you perform over the command window
If that computation is not being designed to a meaningful variable, so when we cover the variable part it will become more evident
The meanings of this workspace window as well some of the other options that you may not hear is
some of the conventional
Conventional buttons that are being there for example you want to create a new script or you want to open certain file as well
Right so similarly there are so many other options, so these are not present in the conventional tools
right, so
then will become more relevant as we progress along with the along with the course right, so
Similarly you may note that
There is another game over here
Which is the plot?
so we will be learning this part [will] [be] [toward] the plot section, so
You can choose from different plotting options
In order to plot the data that are contained [in] your variables
Similarly there is another cave. Which is called the abs so you may consider it. Just like an ape store
Where some of the popular aides they will appear here?
Within the first screen and when you hit this so more option, so then it will give you some specific
specific [aides] for the corresponding
for the corresponding knowledge base for it for instance from computational biology
We have some popular [aides] and then from
from databases we have some and then from tempe digital finance and so many others right, so
I would strongly recommend you to play around with these options in order to get the miller eyes, but now
and then
We will be [covering] and they will become more relevant as we progress along with [e] along the along the course
One more thing [that] is very useful is [that] when you press the up arrow button
Right so a list of commands will appear right so that shows the command history
Whatever we do on this command window it is going to be stored
It is not being lost and it is stored here in the Matlab history right and it also
Assigns a time cake to this so later on if we close it today and let's run it we open it tomorrow
So there will be another cake around with the corresponding command that we are going to execute
Right so these were some of the basic introduction in the end the other
Matlab versions you may find some more windows over here right let me back in majority of the case
The relevant window that we will be working in majority of the time [is] the command window
And then we will also look at the workspace is be progress along with the course right so standing on you in the next lecture
Hello students welcome again to the new segment in this segment
We will go a little bit further and explain some more key concepts in order to understand
Matlab right so in the last lecture we noticed that we can do some basic operations
within this command window
But please note that whenever we do some calculation. We are unable to actually store the result of this calculation
so if you want to store the result into some container
So the Matlab provides you with the with the ability to define variables which will either
Which you can initialize from some value, or it can store the result of some manipulation that you perform?
So in this case it will store the result
So similarly we can perform other operations on these on the variables for example
I want to [multiply] the content of this variable a with 16 by 8 so then the content of a will be
will be updated in this case to
And what important thing to note?
Is that when we update a value of a variable so its previous value is going to be lost?
So if you want to store its previous value as well, there are ways for example. You can define some other variable B
Which will contain its previous value, and then you can update
the variable a so
in that in that case you will not lose the previous value of a right, so
But in [general] whenever you update a single variable its value is going to be lost and the new value [is] going to [be] written
in place of that
Now one thing more [and] we also
discussed this workspace in the previous lectures so it's actually keeping track of all the variables that you are using and
Defining on this command windows right so variable a variable b
We just created them and it contains its corresponding values, right?
so when you double [click] it if this workspace is going to span the entire screen and
When you double click it [again] is going to be minimized
Similarly if you click it over here, right so you can get some more options over here and similarly when you click [here]
You can see some [of] the more statistics right so for example if you want to
Look at the very end or the standard deviation and so many other values right? So it will give you an
information about that
So they don't look people come back again and see what is the correct interpretation of these values when we cover?
Matrices and vectors
So stay tuned for that
Now let us look at some more
operations that we can perform for example if you want to clear up the command window, so
We do a lot [of] manipulation on this command window
And now we want to see a clear command [window] [super] [that] you need you need to use the command
ClC it will clear the [screen] for you, right?
similarly when you press the up arrow Key
it will give you the list of commands that you have been executing since the start of this session right, so
Whenever you come back again later on tomorrow or some [other] day
So there will be a new time cage and correspondingly the list of commands that will that you have executed based on day
Based on that particular day, right, so if you go a little bit app you will see that
There is a time. Take associated with this right, so if we
break it a little bit here right, so
Right so we can see that
The corresponding time cake is always there
And so it is the time [cake] that it is telling us that on 3rd of May
9:53 a.m.. Your session starts right and then these commands will be executed after that session
So later on if you can take tomorrow, you will see another time take responding to that
Ok what do you think more? Is that if you want to take rid of all the variables that are being currently being initialized?
So you need to use the clear commands, right?
So it will clear the command window
Right and it will clear the history so all the [word] [history] are going to be lost
so now if you if you click the up arrow Key
Nothing will show up over here
Right if you want to take rid of all these variables there is another command which is clear all right?
So I don't do it in awhile, but before that
I want to introduce you another command which is whose
So when you click [whose] it will display all the variables that are displayed over here and some more statistics about these variables
so [this] will become more clear as we progress along with the course that what exactly these different themes needs and
when you play
When you write clear also all the variables that you have defined are going to be lost?
and then you can see clc as well to clear the command window, so if you
Want to delete a specific variable, right?
So you can use the clear command and use its name so we can say clear a in this case
It will delete the variable a and the indication will be the instead it will be not showing up in the workspace anymore, right?
So now [n] [is] being deleted, so if you want to delete b as well
You can always do that and the other variant is clear all that will
That will clear all the variables that you have just defined
For a few more basic introductory notes. See you in the next segment
Hello students welcome again to the new segment in the last
segment
We introduced you to the concept of variables that is it contains?
useful and Meaningful data that you want to store in your
Data Mart's stored permanently in your programs
[so] now I'm going and building on top of that
I want you to introduce you to the very basic concept of Matlab
That from where its name originated that is Matrix
laboratory Right Matrix Lab
So that means laboratory and mass transfer Matrix right so Matrix laboratory
So this land has origins in the way that Matlab
Actually handles the variables so by default whatever variable you create
right and
then you
When you look at its side, so it will say 1 Cross 1 so by default
Each and every variable that you define in Matlab it is going to be a matrix
Right and in this case since the Matrix has only one entry so the size of that Matrix is 1 Cross 1
Right so it means the Matrix has only [1] entry
So now a very key question that arise is that we know that the Matrix can be of size 2 Cross 3
Or it can be [upside] 5+5 10 [cross-state] any size right so how we can actually create
Variables that corresponds to those mattresses right so let's do that
Suppose we want to create a matrix now
It is a variable and we know that it's by default it's a Matrix
So how we can actually include more than one item into their metrics
So actually when you want to
have
Individual values into that matrix so you need to separate them by a space and all those values need to be
enclosed using these square brackets and
After entering the value of a particular row if you want to add items for the next row
So then you need to have this semicolon, right?
as
the only restriction here instead, they're
The Metrics should have this the same number of columns right, so it is it contains three columns in this case
So the second row should also contain three column values otherwise it is going to give you some [subjects] errors, right?
So in this case I have created a 3 Cross 3 Matrix
If we look at the look at it again
It will see now the size is 3 Cross 3 right?
So now if you look at the workspace again and double click it so now some of the stuff will become more meaningful
right so now it will show you all the values [that] are contained within this variable a
Right and you can also have a look at some of the more
Step right for example the max value so the max value in this case is
Can similarly the minimum value in the entire Matrix is 7 the variance among the values are?
[0.77]
similarly some other statistics that [in] range be Median mode standard deviation
You can have [located] here as well, right so on the variable [that] you create a using this command window
We are going to appear over here, and then you can choose whichever statistics. You want to have a look at it
so that was a very key concept in understanding Matlab is that each and every variable is by default a
Matrix and then you can enter a multiple values in that Matrix using these square brackets notation
So finally as some more useful operations that you can do here in the workspace. Is that I can click this a
variable right so you can
Have access to some more operations for [example]. You can rename it and give it some other name for example. You can say variable
My variable right and you can always
Duplicate it as well right so now you have two copies of that variable, but remember that the variable name needs to be unique
So in this case. We should give it a more meaningful value. We can say to click it copy
[duplicates] of my variable
So also please note [that] the variable needs do not [continue] any [spaces]
duplicate my copy
my variable
and
Some more operations that are
there are the delete operation and
they did values if you want to edit some values in it you can have access to that and
Then finally one interesting operation is the safe [aids] operation right, so it will save it in the dotnet
extension with a dotnet extension that is a matrix extension and
When you heat it again in the math lab environments the Matlab knows this extension
So it can easily read in a date particular file as well
Let's save it
so now if when we save it we mess
We can access it under different working directory, and then you double click it, right
So it automatically loads that dead for you, right, so it is
It is here and it is being loaded into the method environment
And you can use it if we clear all the variables it will become more clear. That's how we can actually load that
So let me double click it. It's now been loaded and it has appropriate name right, so we leave it again
right and when we double click it you will suddenly note that it will appear in [that] my workspace as well, right, so
That's how you can actually load and save your files
For your mattresses MV. You were hard disk as well
So [that's] enough for this segment in the next segment. We'll be looking at some more operations that are
Available for you on and you can perform them on the Matrices so stay tuned
Hello students welcome again to the segment and inside that we will be looking at some [more] variable types
So the variable type that we have been working so [far] was numeric
so for instance when we say equals to 9 so that the type [of] this variable is automatically set and it is of
numeric type
So the other data types that we may be interested in is the [first] of all is the collector data type
So [then] we say press enter [now] a whole
non-numeric Data and this gate retractor some director values and if you look at its type
So it will say it is a character class character, right, so it is a character array
And by default since everything is a matrix so it's id is 1 plus 11 which means it has 11 characters in it
So please note that the space is also counted as one character in this case
So if we count the hello contains [5] Factors then followed by space which makes it 6 and then 6 more
right, so
It's sorry 5 more, so 6 plus 9 equals 11, so it has now
Characters in Total So if you want to make it of 2 Plus 11
so you can I mention it like this then you want to say that you want to insert the second row and
This column actually means that corresponding to [all] columns in this case
I want to assign it the values that are stored in a in a 1 and
All the Columns corresponding today
So the row 1 of a the 8th the second row of is will be
the exactly the same [in] the first rule of a
respond to all Columns when you press enter and
We'll get it again. So now a is 2 Rows corresponding to 11 columns
So one restriction on this
particular character array is that
Always you need always to have the same size for the rows
So if we want to let's say a of three corresponding to all
All Columns, we want to assign some other values for it for example. [we] say
All right, how are you? So it will give us an error, right?
And it's because it is not of the same size in the earlier
As the earlier rules are and because of that it returns an error
so if we make it exactly the same side, so we say [3] [4] [5] [6] [7] [8] [9] 10 and then LN
So it will not give us an error
so if we want to stir
my characters of having various sizes so for that purpose we need to create strings and
The string of Data type is actually
initialized using this
Reserve board string, so by [reservoir] [TV]. That Matlab is going to use it for its own purposes
so you cannot use it in your programs or
When you were writing some spread so you cannot use this word that is string, right?
It's reserved for Matlab manipulation so we can say equals to string and then you can define
the first element of that string and
Then let's say we want the first element to be this one. Hi, how are you?
Right so now it's st.. It is of type string and it's supposed element in this one
so if you want [to] store multiple elements into this
into this
right so we can enclose it within this square bracket now it means we are giving it multiple values and
they are going to depart of
of the same
Variable Matrix a and [we] can give it a variable length of the strings right so we can say hello world in this case
and
Then we can enclose it right so now it contains a 1 cross 2 string array which means that if we look at it it
Impose, so it means it is of size 1 Cross 2 and each of them is having a different size, right?
Similarly if we want to insert another row into it
Right so we can insert something else in the play control and we can say
My name into it
But remember that since it is a matrix so you need to insert two more strings over here
[and] of course they can be variable and
So now it will be a to process to string that the first value. [there's] [a] second value is 2/3 and the support value
Someone more important important topic [that] we miss is that how we can actually accept that individual elements of a Matrix?
So that purpose we need to use this
This round shade to break it and then we can mention that
[their] corresponding row element that [we] want to access and the corresponding column
right so 1 comma 1 is this particular element this is the
second element which is which has an index of 1 comma 2 we need the first row second column and then this is the
Second row first Column so 2 comma 1 and then this is 2 comma 2 which means second row second column
So you press enter it will return the first value and then if you want to access the second value
So you need to say 1 comma 2 which in this case is this one so in general the first argument here will
Correspond to the Rule and the second argument here it will correspond to the column so similarly if we have a matrix
inverse Matrix
and
if we want to access this element
so it is located in the second row and in the second column so you can say poutama -
sorry - drama - and it will return the first column element similarly for this one it is 1 comma 3
That's how you can actually access the individual Elements within [a] particular Matrix
and you can always do some operation on that you can say what comma 3
equals to
9 plus
1 so only that element is going to be up to is not right so we have performed a particular operation only on that particular
element of [Metrics]
When our final loan is that it is another Data type?
[it] is called the logical Data type
and it's very important in order to make some data selection or make some useful a
decision in within your program right so in order to Define a logical
Variable you need to say logical
And then you can first
Define the
Values that you want to take part in this logical
induced electrical
Matrix, so I want to define it as to
So remember that this logical
Token will only return either 1 or 0 so when you define a variable is logical it can hold only
two values either 1 or 0
Actually if you might [see] state mention something greater than 1
So it will be automatically demoted to 1 right so now instead of this 8 we have a 1 over [here]
right let's corresponding to this element and
We will look at the logical very
Very soon in some of our next segment
but for now
just remember that a lot of variables into 10 two values 1 and 0 and they are used in order to select some data or
Make some useful decision within your program
[so] state the own even the next segment
Hello students welcome again to the new segment and this segment we will be looking at how to create scripts
and few more important notions and concepts, so
basically
Let me create some variables are meaningful variables, which we already did right
so we have created a to cross for what you can array in last segment and
let us say we [have] to create some more variables for example B, and
C equals to work a poly pipe and so on
[so] one thing is that
We may be interested in saving our work
in a separate file, so that later on the weekend tomorrow, we see ever work [a]
The whole thing that we performed in a [single] place
So one way to do that is to create scripts and write your code in here
Rather than executing them individually on the command window, so in order to create script one way is to
Press the up arrow Key and Select both commands music. You are interested in
And including it in your script, right so let's say [I'm] [pressing] on these two
So we right click on that?
So we will have an option [that] is saying create script you click that another window will appear over here
Right and you can actually use this window in order to write your programs now right similarly we can say
[B]
[Plus] C
like and we can enter as many commands as we want and
Then the next step is to save it in some proper place and by default
The default directory is going to appear right and you will give it a meaningful name to this file
For example we can say it's Subside [1]
and
remember that it's extension is going to be dot [m] file right and
Again, if it now so that file you can now find it over here in the current folder directory
If you save it in some other place
So make sure you can current directory today directly here the [ballot] increase and you can always change it like this, right?
Okay, so what we have written this [code]
We can and we want it and now remember [that] this code is not in the command window. So how we can run this code
So basically you can run it by pressing this run button over here, and it will run all the corresponding code for you
And if there is any output it is going to appear here in your command windows
And so when we press it and so first of all it
Actually executes this statement that is equal to 39 and then equals to 45 and then the corresponding result
[so] to note that you [should] not here is that?
Firstly, we actually do not want this output to be to be appearing on the command window
so if you want to
If you want in this case that this should not [clear] right you want only the result appear so you should put a semicolon
At the end of the [statement] and now it will not when you b execute this command
This program so these take these first two statements is not going to be part of your output and only this is going to appear
as an output right
Human wrote
the first thing [that] you should not here is that
When you open this script?
So you may notice [that] there are some additional options that are appearing here at the top?
So this is basically automatic in Matlab and the Matlab actually
Recognizes the current work or the current task that you are currently being performing and according to that it is going to update this
automatically, right
Similarly there are few more options
and we will look at it later on in this course and [they] become very much relevant in the next part of this course [a]
Final note is that
you may also be interested in writing some some explanation of the commands that you are entering so in order to
To do that you need to insert some comments
So the comments are part of your of your [scripts] which are not going to be executed as part of the program
so if I write that this is the
declaration
for the variable B, right and
Similarly I can add an additional statement over here. This is the
declaration
For the variable C. And I can add another comment over here, and I can say this is [your] final [result]
so [when] I execute this program
These statements are not going to be executed right so the Matlab automatically recognize that this
Anything that starts with with this?
Person time it is going to be
It is going to be a comment, and it is just explanation of the code so I do not need to execute this right
So that's how you can eat some extra explanation in order to understand you were called Meaningfully
when [journal] mode is that
Please to remember that there are all these multiple ways of doing the thinking when you are considering the Matlab environment
So the other way to create scripts is to go to this new file and say
Inspect right so it will appear over here, and then you can write the whole code over here again
right and you can say
And then you can have equals to C plus b
[right], so this is essentially the same and when you try to run it it is for you to save it first
so we can say exercise 1 1
And then it will run in execute that code as well
So two ways to create script is first of all [to] so you may select it from the [commandment]
Don't almost command that you are interested in and the second way [is] to just use this plus sign
And it will create a new script for you
So see you in the next segment hopefully during the course
Hello students welcome again to the new section and to the new segment of the course
[in] this segment we will be looking at some common math operations that you can perform in Matlab that is addition
subtraction [multiplication] and
others
[so] we know that from our basic knowledge that everything in in the Matlab is
Every variable in that life is treated in the form of a Matrix
Let us Define a Matrix
Let's say we have
a 2 cross 3 Matrix and then we Define another Matrix which is
obtained size
Right so in order to perform the subtraction
Operation so you just need to say a minus b. And it will do the matrix subtraction
operation that is the corresponding increase will be subtracted [from] each other that is 1 minus 5 is minus 4 2
Minus 8 is minus 6 and so on
Similarly you can perform the matrix multiplication operation
but in order to perform the multiplication
operation there is a restriction the
Columns of the first Matrix that is going to be part of that multiplication
should make the
Rows of the second Matrix that is going to be part of the multiplication
So in this case a cross [p] will give you an error
because the
Dimensions must agree, right, so that's the year so in order to make it happen
[we] can take transpose of the second Matrix so and other to take transpose of a Matrix
It is very simple. We just need to say B and this
this sign in
Along with b. That is very on my keyboard. It's very close to [the] to the inter button
And it also shows the double quotes on on top of that
So if you press it with a single code it is going to perform the Matrix transpose operation
so now we have
We have the corresponding
corresponding to metrics based on that we can perform the matrix multiplication operation and
Model to do that. We know that the columns here are making the rows here. [so] now we are ready to go and
We can perform the corresponding Matrix
Multiplication operation right similarly there is another variant and which is the element by element multiplication?
Operation so if you don't want to have a matrix multiplication [rather] you want
an Element by element multiplication
So that is also possible
[so] let's say we want to multiply each and every element of a with itself
So that is not possible
Actually this in text was not correct, so that's the actual syntax of that in this case
We don't need the Matrix to have
Like the restriction on the Matrix multiplication is [not] there rather
we just need the two matrix to be on the same side right so a dot a
similarly if we take the transpose of B again
Right so we can perform a dot star b as well
So in this case it [is] performing Matrix
Element by element multiplication, [so] this one is multiplied by this one right so we have the corresponding result over here
Right so similarly if we look at a right?
So this mind was being multiplied by the corresponding element here B
Which is 8 so 19 to 8 is 72 so that was the corresponding answer similarly this 8 was being multiplied by 10?
So [that] the corresponding answer over here
So that was how you can do
the Element by Element multiplication
within a Matrix
[ok] so in the same way you can always do the Matrix addition
Operation as well, so that will aid the corresponding Elements [NMDa] right So 5
So if we just play the [2] matrices, so this was Matrix B
This was Matrix a and this is the corresponding is also 5 plus 1 6 and then 8 plus 2 10 and so on
It's the variables that you are using [are] [not] matrices
They are single variables right so 1 cross 1 Matrices right so all these operations are still valid and they can be done, right?
So a minus b
it is a valid operation right similarly a plus B, and
Similarly a multiplied by B. Right so you can always do that?
Okay, [well] final operation
Is that if you want to take the power of a certain variable like so I want the second power of I want the square?
Of the of the a right, so this is designed for that, right?
So this will compute the square of the really
So it was initially having a value of [I] and now a multiplied by a is 81
So that's the corresponding operation. Similarly it can be a fraction number as well, right or it can be a whole number or
[it] can be anything, so if it is a complex
Equation like this you can still still it is still possible, right, so it is equivalent to
[1.5] power of a right, so if we say 1.5, so it's the same answer
One final note is that when you apply this matrix operation on to our Matrix
so it lands has to result which you should note then when we take the second power of a
So what does it mean in this case in this case?
It will multiply a with a right, so it will be returning the result of Matrix multiplication
right, so if you
Did you perform that oh?
Yes, it is giving us an error message because for the Metros multiplication and the two Matrix
Columns the first
The Columns of first Matrix must match the rows of the second Matrix and indicated in that case so a must be a square Matrix
So let's define a square matrix in this is and now we can perform a spirit
So a square in this case is a cross a result of matrix multiplication
Right so if you want and if you are interested in not a matrix multiplication, [but] rather you want to take
the per second power of a yard or the square of each and
Individual element right so in order to do that
We just need to put a dot over here and it will now compute the element right square of each Entry within this Matrix
So if you don't put the dot it is going to compute the Matrix
The Matrix operation there is a into a write the matrix result of that the matrix multiplication is about that
So there were a few notes, and of course there are other ways [to] compute the square as well so stay tuned
Hello students welcome again to the new segment in this segment we will be looking gate operation
[residents] what exactly we mean by that that suppose we have an expression such as this one
Right and [when] you press enter it will give you nine, right?
But you may note that there are two operations involved
What is the addition and the other one is a subtraction?
so which one was being executed first if you look at it it first compute [it] and then it the
Result is being added with ten right so in this case minus one plus. Ten is nine
however if you change the position of this a right
So initially we have 8 here in front if you put it here now
It will give you a different result, right?
So we have the same expression more or less and now
You have to change the order of each of the variables and that it gives you it gives you a completely different result
So [high] actually it works
right, so
When the Matlab is going to execute this first and very it's going to execute this first right so similarly if you have very complex
Complex expressions that is this one, right?
So then it becomes more harder to to do to look at like
What is what is actually the order in which it performs these different operations?
so the Matlab has a
Has the same systems that we usually do in math and that?
You can remember the formula both, mass
so
But do exactly read my days
is that first of all it will handle any brackets [if] they are being present within an expression and
Then it will do the division
If the division is there that it will do multiplication and then addition and finally subtraction
for the other operations that is the unary operations which we will look at later on and
similarly the
Operations such as the dot star operations and power operations, right?
So there are different [presidencies] right so in order to look at the complete the combination of that
There is that search tool that you can use
And this is actually the documentation of the math lab that comes with the copy of your mat lab, right?
so if you right here
operation residence
and then
this
House documentation will appear in [your] screen, and if you click here, so it will give you the complete
documentation and
The precedence in which these different operations are being performed
However the easiest way to ensure any precedence is just use these brackets, right?
so if we have this expression
And I want the multi-day subtraction to me to be performed first right so I can always put you break it
So it will ensure that this operation is going to be performed first and then I want to add up the results
With this stance so I can ensure it like this, so then it will be performed
at
The next level and finally all the result will be that will be multiplied [by] 8 so in this way I can ensure that
corresponding precedence
so this was the first computation in this case the innermost brackets 8 minus 9 is minus 1 and
Then this was the [second-level] brackets, so it was the second operation
So 10 minus 1 is 9 and then 9 into 8 is 72 which was the outermost?
Outermost to break it right, so that's how we can ensure presidents in simplest way I
prefer this way because it is very simple and easy to do right [now] however when the when the a
Venule expression grow bigger so you can always break it into pieces suppose if there is more complex
Operations that are being performed where here is
and
Now there are two parts of this expression and both [of] them are being multiplied together
So if I can break it into two I can assign it to variable B
and
then I will assign it to variable a
right
So there is an error it is because some brackets are being not
Properly assigned let's simplify it is okay, and now let's look at B
So b has some misplaced [parenthesis]
Yes, so one of the brackets were extra so and now we can multiply a into b in order to compute that complex
A
a complex expression
so the easiest way [to] ensure the pistons is to use the brackets and if the
Expression is growing very large, and you can make pieces out of that so you can
You can actually make parts of that and do [it]
In this fashion right so that's how operation pistons work in Matlab
[if] for some reason you do not
You do [not] like to include these brackets
Then you need to conserve this whole documentation in order to see in which order
Different operations are going to be performed however. I prefer this way in this way
It may [depends] on [you're] on your own tries, but I prefer this way. Hope you are enjoying the course using an excitement